<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ricercar</title>
    <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ricercar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Gopichand Kotana</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:43:23 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gopick.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 year retrospective</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/personal/five-year-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 11:43:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/personal/five-year-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>It has been 5 years since I started working. I still work at Goldman, although I don&amp;rsquo;t work with data anymore. I do App development now. In a truly agile way (A 5 year sprint? Don&amp;rsquo;t hire me as your scrum master), I have decided to write a retrospective. What went well? What did not go so well? What could be better? But more importantly, what did I learn?
Before I started working, life was like sprinting on a track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are User-defined types?</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 05:03:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/data-types/</guid>
      <description>User-defined types are a convenience.
People always quote the principles of Object-Oriented Programming as a reason for using classes - Obvious abstraction, free encapsulation, we can inherit all the goodness and, we get that sweet sweet runtime polymorphism.
But?
Abstraction is hard. Finding the right abstractions is hard. Implementing interactions between these abstractions is hard. Encapsulation is essential, but the level of encapsulation provided by object-oriented languages isn&amp;rsquo;t always needed. In many cases, you just need a C style struct and a utility file that has functions that manipulate this data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multithreading Basics (Java examples by chatgpt)</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/multithreading-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:03:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/multithreading-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Multithreading Multithreading is a programming technique that allows multiple threads to run concurrently and parallely within a single process. Parallelism is possible if you have multiple cores available for the threads to run on.
Threads are lightweight execution units within a process. They share the same memory space, resources, and state as the parent process. Each thread has its own program counter, stack, and set of registers, allowing it to execute instructions independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software construction course by MIT</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/software_construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 10:03:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/software_construction/</guid>
      <description>This was a great weekend read. I was familiar with most of the concepts introduced in this course, but it was great to have them introduced in more formal way. The course uses typescript, and I finally got some exposure to it. Maybe as a next step I should use it to build something - something for the future. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great course for people just joining the workforce as software devs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are vector databases? Why are they hot right now?</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/vector-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 05:03:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/vector-databases/</guid>
      <description>So What are Vector Dbs? Vector Dbs are Databases that have native support to store and retrieve vector data. In Deep Learning everything is a vector -&amp;gt; Your inputs, weights, and your learned semantic space and embeddings. Vector Dbs can be used to store and retrieve these artifacts efficiently.
What is the right way of storing and retrieving these vectors? We typically want &amp;lsquo;Similar&amp;rsquo; vectors to be bunched together. We define similarity as the distance between two vectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2022</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/advent-of-code-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 10:03:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/programming/advent-of-code-2022/</guid>
      <description>Diary of AOC 2022. This is my first time attempting AOC. I ended up with 45 stars. My company had a private leaderboard, and I am competitive enough to take the bait. I chose python to solve the puzzles. I know many people use AOC as an opportunity to learn new languages, but I wanted to go with something familiar. I never used python in a professional setting, but I love using it for scripting and writing scrappy code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why This? Why Now?</title>
      <link>https://gopick.github.io/posts/personal/why-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 10:42:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gopick.github.io/posts/personal/why-now/</guid>
      <description>I made an account on Orkut in 2009. In those days, internet connections were expensive and (super)slow. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my own pc, but luckily, one of my uncles got a job in the city as a PhP developer. He stayed with us for a few years and he had a PC that I could use. Most people around me didn’t have any virtual social presence. And no one was bombarded with an insane amount of curated and unnecessary information like we are today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
